thank you guys happy Sabbath once again
everyone let us pray Heavenly Father we
come before you today asking that you
would speak to our hearts Lord may this
message change our relationship with you
in Jesus name we pray amen amen all
right how many have a best friend amen
that's good to know
how many have a couple of best friends
very how many of you have a group of
best friends you have a group of best
friends best friends are a good thing to
have amen yeah so I'm gonna share with
you today a term that maybe you have
heard maybe some of you have not heard
but it's the title of the sermon today
so the time of the sermon today is
simply ride-or-die have you heard that
term before lucy has view of her that
wrought so some of you younger people
have heard maybe others some of you
other younger people may not have heard
the term so let me explain to you what
the term means the term ride-or-die
first began as a biker term any bikers
former bikers ride or die it first began
as a biker term meaning if you couldn't
ride you'd rather die you'd rather die
it has now changed to mean anyone
boyfriend girlfriend wife husband friend
best friend who is just that
a best friend so for example we might
say that someone who will go through any
problem with you
ride or die trying'
the person is called my ride-or-die so
if you have a best friend you have a
ride-or-die right or that someone who
will be honest with you at all times is
that how your best friend is or your
best friend's are they're honest with
you
all the time a loyal friend a loyal
friend that will do anything for you
a ride-or-die is someone that sticks
with you through thick and thin a
ride-or-die never betrays you all right
or die doesn't hold your mistakes and
your shortcomings against you how many
of you have best friends ride or dies
yeah so that's a ton of the message so I
want you to get the context ride or die
ride or die every one of us in our lives
have you know a few of those people that
we would consider ride or die friends
until the end and the Bible actually has
a addresses this very kind of friendship
it's found in John chapter 15 and verse
13 John chapter 15 and verse 13 the
Bible says here and see tell me if you
think this matches that the the
definition that we just spoke about John
John 15:13 greater love greater love has
no man than this that he lay his life
down for his friends do you think that's
a good definition of ride-or-die
yeah that's a ride-or-die type of
friendship greater love has no man than
this that a man lay down his life for
his friends so I want to tell you about
a special ride-or-die friend who you
think that's
special ride-or-die friend is it is
Jesus Jesus is our ultimate ride-or-die
amen and amen
Jesus is our ultimate ride and I he said
to his father I'm going down to earth to
ride with my friends that's what he said
in fact in Isaiah 59 verse 16 and 17 the
Bible says here and he saw that there
was no man and wondered that there was
no intercessor therefore his arm brought
salvation unto him and his righteousness
it sustained him for he put on
righteousness as a breastplate and a
helmet of salvation upon his head and he
put on the garments of vengeance for
clothing and he was clad with zeal as a
cloak in other words what this verse is
telling us here is that Jesus had our
friendship so heavily upon his heart
that he was willing he looked down here
and saw that there was no one
interceding for mankind that mankind was
headed toward destruction and he himself
said I will go down and ride with them
man that's a weak amen for a ride and
die kind of friend Christ said I'm gonna
come down and I'm going to I'm going to
live life with them I'm going to ride
with them so Philippians 2 verses 5
through 7 tells us let this mind be in
you which was also in Christ Jesus who
being in the form of God thought it not
robbery to be equal with God but made
himself of no reputation and took upon
him the form of a servant and was made
in the likeness of men I want you to
understand this God God gave up heaven
to be our ride-or-die friend
that's how deep it is when you talk
about deep friendships I want you to
think about your best friend or your
group of best friends why are they your
best friends and you know the reason why
is because they would do anything for
you they are ride-or-die kind of friends
well here Jesus is demonstrating to us
listen guys this is how much I love you
as a friend I was willing to leave
heaven for you to come down to this
earth to become one of you so Matthew
1:21 tells it this way Matthew chapter 1
and verse 21 the Bible says and she
shall bring forth a son and thou shalt
call his name Jesus for he shall save
his people from their sins now all this
was done that it might be fulfilled
which was spoken of the Lord by the
Prophet saying behold a virgin shall be
with child and she shall bring forth a
son and they shall call his name
Emmanuel which being interpreted is God
what everyone with us not want you to
think about that your best friend is
your best friend because your best
friend is always hanging out with you
right you're not best friends and not
have to spend time together that's not
what a best friend does best friends
spend time together so Bible the Bible
is telling us that God came in the flesh
to ride with us God with us he was
coming to partake of our lie he was
coming to partake of our flesh partake
of our our likeness because he loved us
in fact hebrews chapter 2 verse 14 tells
it this way Hebrews chapter 2 verse 14
Hebrews chapter 2 verse 14 we're going
to read all the way through to verse 18
is it up there on the screen right he
brews chapter 2 verse 14 the Bible says
for as much than us as the children are
partakers of flesh and blood he also
himself likewise took part of the same
that through death he might destroy him
that had the power of death that is the
devil and delivered them who through
fear of mark of the fear of death were
all their lifetime subject to bondage
for verily he took not on him the nature
of angels but he took on him the seed of
Abraham wherefore in all things it
behooves him to be made like unto his
brethren that he might be a merciful and
faithful high priest in things
pertaining to God and to make
reconciliation for the sins of the
people for in that he himself has
suffered being tempted he is able also
to succour them that are tempted in
other words Jesus came down to this
earth to become one of us and to live
like us in other words he came to ride
with us he said I'm not gonna let you go
through this alone
I am your ride or die wait remember when
Jesus was when Jesus went into the
wilderness remember that story and do
you remember how as he goes into the
wilderness in Matthew chapter 4 turn
there with me if you will Matthew
chapter 4 verse 1 and 2 I need you to
see this Matthew chapter 4 verse 1 and 2
now if you chapter 4 verse 1 and 2 the
Bible says then was Jesus led up into
the spirit into the wilderness to be
tempted of the devil and when he had
fasted 40 days and 40 nights he was
afterward hungry see you didn't let you
hmm okay I got a question for you how
many of you have best friends alright
has your best friend ever fasted 40 days
and 40 nights for you okay you want to
talk about ride-or-die you want to talk
about a friend who would be willing to
go all out for you beloved the reason
that Jesus fasted 40 days and four
nights was to try to prove to you I need
you to understand how much I am your
ride or die
Jesus fasts 40 days for his friends he's
like no those my people I'm gonna do
this for them and then after the fast
the Bible says that the devil came to
him in the wilderness to tempt him turn
this stone to bread you know what he was
really asking him to do think about it
if Jesus had turned that stone into
bread where would he have left us yeah
he would have left left us without hope
if Jesus had given into this temptation
what would happen to his friends yeah
what would happen to his friends they
would die so you know what Jesus a Jesus
in other words what I'm telling you is
that Jesus overcame temptation on behalf
of his the reason Jesus resisted Turning
Stone to bread the reason Jesus resisted
bowing down is because the devil was
basically saying hey betray your friends
nope nope no I'm not gonna betray them
jesus is our ride-or-die
Jesus overcomes off
best friend me see your hand again how
many of you was saying right now that
Jesus has already outdone your best
friend this is your best friend your
ride-or-die on planet earth and yet
Jesus has already outdone your best
friend
so how ride-or-die is Jesus how
ride-or-die is how much is he really
willing to go the distance with us come
with me to the book of Matthew 26
Matthew 26 and by the way I got to tell
you something
we're only studying the foundation
because this sermon is on the seven
seals of the book of Revelation I know
you're like wait a minute pastor how do
we just get there just bear with me I'm
gonna show you something Jesus is our
ride-or-die
come Matthew 26 Matthew 26 and and and
notice with me verse 31
talk about a ride-or-die kind of friend
Matthew 26 verse 31 then save Jesus unto
them that is the disciples all you shall
be offended because of me this night for
it is written I will smite the Shepherd
and the Sheep of the flock shall be
scattered but after I am risen again I
will go before you into Galilee and
Peter answered and said unto Him though
all men shall be offended because of
thee yet will I never be offended and
Jesus said unto Him verily I say unto
thee that this night before the
crow thou shalt deny me what three times
let me tell you something about
ride-or-die type of friends a
ride-or-die friend is still your
ride-or-die friend even when you don't
do right Peter Jesus
I got you I want you to know that I and
your writer die I will go all out for
you Peter Jesus and Jesus knowing the
weakness of his friend knowing the
weakness of his friend and tells him
because a ride-or-die friend is honest
amen
yeah
straight
in-system Peter listen um you don't know
yourself as well as I know you you're
gonna be you are going to forsake me I
tell you
beloved ride-or-die friends don't hold
your faults against you can you say Amen
so Jesus he's trying to show us listen
this is how much I am ride-or-die for
you
Matthew 26 verse 38 Matthew 26 verse 38
the Bible says here then cometh Jesus
with them onto a place called Gethsemane
and saith unto his disciples sit here
while I go and pray yonder and he took
with him Peter and the two sons of
Zebedee and began to be sorrowful and
very heavy and and then saith unto them
my soul is exceeding sorrowful even unto
death tarry ye here and watch wat with
me and he went a little further and fell
on his face and prayed saying O my
father if it be possible let this cup
pass from me nevertheless not as I will
but as thou well do you realize why
Jesus decided that he would drink the
cup as hard as that would be it was
because Jesus was our ride or die I'm
not leaving them alone I'm not turning
my back on them those are my people's
you know in the world said you those are
my peeps Jesus those are my people I'm
not leaving them I I will ride I will
ride Jesus he's praying in the garden
and then when he gets up he goes to his
friends you know the ones that he's
willing to ride or die for and what are
they doing sleeping see beloved a
ride-or-die friend is your friend
did you catch that a ride-or-die friend
is your friend even when you sleep on
them that's what I meant to say even
when you sleep on them beloved I want
you to understand
that is not really a we don't really
understand that Jesus is our ride-or-die
we kind of approach him in a fearful way
we approach them like we kind of hold
things from him beloved tell me which
one of you holds things from your best
friend your best friend is the one
person you can say hey listen don't tell
anybody but is that right that's the
best friend hey don't tell anyone but
Jesus is that best friend he is that
ride-or-die even when we sleep on him he
does not turn his back on us how much
Matthew 26 Matthew 26 verse 50 verse 56
Matthew 26 verse 56 the Bible says here
and they that had laid hold on Jesus lay
I'm sorry verse 56 but all this was done
that the scriptures of the prophets
might be fulfilled then all the
disciples forsook him and woe now if you
forsook your best friend and fled would
that still be your best friend your best
friend MA he might be like hey I forgive
you or she might be like I forgive you
but it'd be very difficult Jesus this is
how much he was ride-or-die for us that
even in his greatest crisis when his
friends forsook him he never for cick
them come how much how far was Jesus
willing to ride or die for us Matthew 26
verse 66 Matthew 26 and verse 66 the
Bible says then the high priest on
Sarver 666 what thinking they answered
and said he is guilty of death he is
guilty of lot death then they spit in
his face
and buffeted him and others smote him
with the palms of their hand saying
prophesy unto us Christ who is it that
smote thee now I got a question for you
how many of your friends would take a
beating for you how many of you friends
would take getting spit in the face and
profited and marked in front of large
crowds of people for you now your friend
might be willing to go and fight for you
and with you but probably not take a
voluntary beating for you you want to
know how much Christ was ride-or-die
this is how much he was right or die he
was willing to be beaten and spat upon
and mocked and ultimately we know that
the Bible says in Matthew 27 no.3
Matthew 27 verse 31 here's what the
Bible says Matthew 27 verse 31 and they
took him and mocked him they took his
robe off of him and put his own raiment
on him and led him away to be crucified
and they put him up on the cross and
then they began to say if you're the Son
of God what come down do you know the
devil because the devil was inspiring
that do you know what the devil was
trying to say what was he trying to say
leave your friends forsake them don't go
through this for them
don't don't don't allow yourself to be
treated this way for them look at this
they don't even deserve you your own
have forsaken you one of your own
betrayed you come on come down jesus is
our ride-or-die
why because he was willing to actually
die and that's exactly what he did and
in that moment he says Father forgive my
friends forgive my friends let me ask
you something what does Jesus just done
what has he just done he is just proving
to us that he is truly our ride
and die so John 14 Jesus before he left
he sets these disciples
I'm going to prepare a place for you I'm
going to do what okay so why does he say
that because when you have a best friend
do you like to be around your best
friend
yeah so after Jesus demonstrates to us
that he is our ride and die he now says
listen by the way I am going away but I
love you guys so much that I'm going to
prepare a place for you
there you may be also
Jesus demonstrates to us that he is
alright and die or die and then he says
I'm going to a place and I'm going to
prepare a place for you so now here we
are on earth our best friend has left us
where did he go where'd he go heaven
come with me Revelation chapter 14
chapter 4 Revelation chapter 4 so he
goes to heaven I hope you're following
this story Jesus left heaven because he
said I'm gonna go down there and I'm
gonna be there ride or die I'm gonna
ride with them and I'm gonna go so far
as to actually die for them he dies is
buried resurrected ascends to heaven and
now we pick up with the scene with Jesus
in heaven Revelation chapter 4
revelation 4 beginning with verse 1 and
the Bible tells us here and after this I
looked and behold a door was open in
heaven and the first voice which I heard
was as it were of a trumpet talking with
me which said come up hither and I will
show thee things which must be Hereafter
and immediately ours in the spirit and
the whole the throne was set in heaven
and one sat on the throne he that sat on
the throne was to look upon like a
Jasper and a sardine stone and there was
a rainbow round about the throne in the
sight like unto an emerald and round
about the throne were four and 20 seats
and upon the seats I saw four and twenty
elders sitting clothed in white raiment
and they had on their heads crowns of
gold and out of the throne proceeded
lightnings and thunderings and voices
and there were seven lamps of fire
burning before the throne which are the
seven spirits of God come with me to
Revelation chapter five Revelation
chapter 5 verse 1 the Bible says I saw
in the right hand of him that sat on the
throne a book written on the backside
sealed with seven seals and I saw a
strong angel proclaiming a loud voice
who is worthy to open the book and to
loose the seals thereof and no man in
heaven nor in earth nor under the earth
were able to open the book to look
thereon and I wept much because no man
was found worthy to open and to read the
book neither to look thereon pause one
second John sees his vision of this
throne in heaven
he sees the one sitting on the throne
the father this book in his hand and
then this book has seals or a sealed and
no one is able to open the book and John
begins to weep why because that book has
to do with our eternal destiny and he is
weeping because no one is found worthy
to open the book what's gonna happen to
humanity and then and then verse six
verse five and one of the elders said
unto me weep not behold the Lion of the
tribe of Judah the root of David has
prevailed to open the books to book and
the book and to loose the seven seals
thereof and I beheld and lo in the midst
of the throne and of the four beasts and
in the midst of the elders stood a lamb
as it had been want slain having seven
horns and seven eyes which are the seven
spirits of God sent forth into all the
earth and he came and took the book out
of the right hand of him that sat on the
throne and when he had taken the book
the four beasts and four and twenty
elders fell down before the lamb having
every one of them harps and golden vials
full of odours which were which are the
prayers of the saints and they sung a
new song saying thou art worthy to take
the book and to open the seals thereof
for thou was slain and has redeemed us
to God by thy blood out of every kindred
tongue people and nation in other words
Jesus opens the book on our behalf hold
on a second he comes to earth he said I
want you to know I'm your ride or die
and this is how much I'm a rider doc I'm
not only willing to ride with you but I
will also die for you he dies and goes
to heaven he says by the way I'm coming
I'm going to prepare a place for you and
I'm coming back to receive you but Lord
how are you going to receive us if
what's gonna happen with us as you have
left so he lets us know listen when I
get to heaven I am going to speak to my
father on behalf of you I'm your ride or
die
I will never forget you I want you to
know how much of a friend I am that I
will go back home and represent you to
my father father I have some friends
down there they're my best friends I am
their ride-or-die friend and so I listen
we need to open this book so that they
can know what's coming because I want to
meet them again in heaven
and so I'm going to give them every
opportunity to be fully prepared for
what's coming so that they have every
chance to live eternally with me forever
they're right or die friend you talk
about ride-or-die you talk about best
friend Jesus is it so he takes his book
and he opens it up and now notice what
the Bible says in revelation 6 verse 1
and I went here and when I saw the lamb
opened up opened one of the seals I
heard as it were the noise of thunder
and one of the four beasts saying come
and see
and I saw and behold a white horse and
he that sat on him had a bow and a crown
was given unto him and he went forth
conquering and to conquer okay you got
it you gotta get this there is a rider
on a white horse a writer a writer a
writer a writer and this rider is on a
white horse now the prophetic and
historical application is of this is
very simple after Jesus ascends to
heaven white represents purity after
this is a sense to heaven this
Whitehorse is seen going through the
earth conquering and to conquer it is a
symbol of the gospel going forth into
the whole world in fact if you read
Revelation chapter 19 verse 11 Jesus is
said to be the rider on a white horse
and his name is called the word of God
so the first seal is the word of God
going forth in the early Christian
church amen
so check this out what Jesus does what
Jesus has done in sending this white
horse it's like he it's like he says hey
listen guys you have a race to run don't
you yeah we have a race to run well I
tell you what you can run a race much
faster if you run it on a horse
this right horse symbolizing the gospel
going forth my friends I want you to get
on this white horse I want you to ride I
want you to ride this is your horse I'm
sending this horse to you this gospel
horse because this is going to be the
horse that rides you that takes you to
where I am get on this horse it's like
imagine Jesus coming back symbolically
on that white horse and he's got a hand
extended for you come on get on ride or
die ride or die listen there's an enemy
after you there's an enemy trying to
destroy you I'm not gonna leave you
alone I've sent you help the gospel get
on this horse guys come on hurry up we
don't have much time ride
right get on now this horse with you can
run a race much faster on a horse than
you can on foot so he sends this gospel
horse and he says get on I told you I
was coming back for you I've got to
prepare a place for you but in the
meantime I'm sending you the gospel get
on this horse get on ride ride ride
listen to get on a horse cost something
you see Jesus is saying to us hey
remember how I rode and died for you
remember that I demonstrated to you that
I was your ride or die friend right yeah
did I prove that to you
yeah can we go through and just remember
the history what I did for you remember
that all right now since I have proved
to you that I am your ride or die friend
that you can trust me will you will you
come on come on come on
I want you to be with me but in order
for you to be with me you got to be with
me man you got to be my so now the story
flips you guys we become his ride or die
because he was first our ride or die he
says come on follow me
ride or die come with me get on the
horse listen Romans five six senses for
when we were yet without strength in due
time Christ died for the ungodly
wait a minute hold on a second ride or
die he died for his friends and what he
does call his friends
yeah wait a minute now hold on a second
I want you to think that through Jesus
the righteous holy one looks at the
ungodly and says I'm gonna ride or die
I'm gonna come down to become one of you
I'm gonna come down to take on flesh and
blood I'm going to come down and no I'm
not gonna sing with you but I will ride
or die for you and so the Bible says he
died for the ungodly for scarcely for a
righteous man will one die yet
peradventure for a good man some may
even dare to die but God commended his
love toward us in that while we were yet
sinners Christ died for us
much more than now being justified by
his blood we shall be saved from wrath
through him for if when we were enemies
we were reconciled to God by the death
of his son much more being reconciled
shall we be saved by his life so in
other words he's saying you guys I had
to prove my ride-or-die status you I had
to demonstrate it and now that I've done
that I'm sending the gospel to you will
you ride or die for me will you ride or
die for me it's our turn remember
greater love has no man than he give it
to me in our language then he ride or
die for his friend you don't look
excited you don't look like you're
really interested in riding and dying
for Jesus riding or dying for Jesus
Jesus said I want you to ride or die for
me greater love has no man than this
then he lay his life down for his friend
check this out
this horse both goes forth conquering
and to conquer how many of you want to
conquer if you want to conquer get on
this horse if you want to conquer in
your Christian walk get on this horse
the Bible says in the book of Romans
that neither life nor death nor trial or
tribulation or persecution shall be able
to separate
from the love of God that is in other
words because he ride and died for her
he rode and died for us we are able to
conquer when we get on that horse we are
able to conquer persecution trial
tribulation everything that Satan has
designed to separate us from God God
says you get on this horse and you will
conquer you'll conquer what are you
gonna cover you're gonna conquer trials
how about conquering self and if you
have trouble conquering self it's better
you know it's better to fight self on a
horse you have a massive advantage get
on that horse the Bible says let us lay
aside the sin that does the weight that
does so easily beset us and run with
patience the race that is set before us
whoa so wait a minute I would rather run
the race on a horse than on foot since
not only that but if I'm on a horse that
conquers then that horse that that that
spirit of conquering I can use that
spirit of conquering to conquer my own
habits of our own trials listen a die or
ride friend you can you can tell them
anything you can tell a ride-or-die
friend when you're struggling you can
tell a ride-or-die friend I fallen and I
can't get up
the rider died friend is not going to
look and say you fell what no he's gonna
say I hear you man come on I'm not
leaving you there can't drop my hand
come on get back up and he will pull you
back up on that horse if any man sin he
has an advocate with the father in other
words Jesus telling us listen I don't
treat me as some out there God who you
can't talk to who you can't be real with
be real with him that's what real
friendship is about God listen I am
struggling with this thing
I'm struggling with this be real with
him and God says listen I will help you
because a true friend will never leave
you down
and Jesus is that ride-or-die friend
that will never leave us down conquer
what conquer trials conquer tribulation
conquer our own cells and our own sins
but he also gives us a commission to go
out into the world and to preach the
gospel get on the horse ride the horse
the gospel wood will advance much faster
if we take it by horse rather than by
foot get on the horse
why else should you get on a horse very
simple but love it because listen the
reason you should get on that white
horse is because you cannot outrun a
horse you can out ride a horse but you
cannot outrun a horse you say pastor
what are you talking about just look at
the very next verse verse 3 and when he
had opened the second seal I heard the
second beast say come and see and there
went out another horse that was red and
power was given to him that sat thereon
to take peace from the earth and that
they should kill one another and there
was given him a great sword you see
beloved behind the white horse is a red
horse and that red horse comes to
persecute to kill the Bible says in the
book of Matthew because iniquity shall
abound the love of many will wax cold
that red horse represents strife in a
very practical sense that would that
occurred in the Roman Empire persecution
of the early Christian church but I but
that's not the application I'm looking
at today what I'm looking at is this
when you get on a white horse know that
the Red Horse is close behind because
they that live godly will suffer
persecution that red horse
Eliza's hatred so cancel beloved you
need to outride hate and you can't
outrun a horse so if you want to escape
that red horse if you want to out ride
the red horse guess what you better be
on that white horse do you understand
what I'm saying many of us are getting
consumed by that red horse because we're
running on foot Jesus is literally
saying to us listen guys ride or if you
don't get on this horse there's another
one coming right behind it that is out
to take your life hatred of this world
the strife of this world the anger of
this world it's all coming after you and
the only way you can outrun it the only
way you can outpace it is by being on a
horse yourself get on that horse ride or
die there's a third horse in verse 4 or
verse 5 rather the Bible system when he
had opened the third seal I burn I held
if I heard the third beast say come and
see and I beheld and lo a black horse
and he that sat on him had a pair of
balances in his hand and I heard a voice
in the midst of the four beasts say a
measure of wheat for a penny and three
measures of barley for a penny and see
thou hurt not the oil of the wine this
third horse a black horse has a pair of
scales in his hands and these scales
represent compromise
what are they compromising the Bible
says it is wheat and barley
what does wheat and barley make it makes
bread which is the word of God and
soaping of it in a literal sense this
occurred when the early church began to
compromise in a time of Constantine
mixing good and evil but let me make it
a practical personal application is very
simply this Satan is out to lead you to
compromise to compromise the word of
truth a little bit of good in your
experience and a little bit of that he
wants you to compromise because in so
doing you lose out on what Christ wants
for you so Jesus says ride or die why
because
behind the white horse is a red horse
seeking to persecute behind that red
horse is a black horse trying to get you
to compromise good and evil there's a
fourth horse is called a pale horse and
beloved listen to me this pale horse the
Bible says that death and hell were the
ones that sat on it
think about that death and hell what is
the purpose of death and hell think
about it as a rider symbolically they're
going out to what to kill do you
understand why Jesus is saying ride or
die
he's saying I need you to stay on this
horse because there are other elements
coming coming that are trying to to
destroy your Christian walk in a very
practical sense this fourth horse
represents the period of the Dark Ages
where where that which appeared to be
good was purely evil under the under the
guy under the disguise of Christianity
but watch this in the very next seal
we've just gone through four seals there
are only two more seals three more seals
actually the Bible says in Revelation 6
and verse verse 9 and when he opened the
fifth seal I saw under the altar the
souls of them that were slain for the
word of God and for the testimony which
they held and they cried with a loud
voice saying how long O Lord holy and
true does thou not judge and avenge our
blood on them that dwell on the earth
and white robes were given unto every
one of them and it was said unto them
that they should rest yet for a little
season until their fellow-servants also
and their brethren should be killed as
they were should be fulfilled do you
know what's happening here this
persecution being spoken about is a
persecution of the that occurred during
the Reformation we're seeing church
history unfold from the time of Christ
all the way down to our time but check
this out these people were willing these
people proved that what Christ did on
the cross for them was so profound that
they in turn became he
yeah they were actually willing to them
that's how that's how much we are Fred
that's how much Jesus is my friend that
we are willing to ride or die for him if
necessary and then comes at six sealed
and in that sixth seal whoo check this
out guys
you know the sixth seal revelation 12
are they held at I beheld when he opened
the sixth seal and lo there was a great
earthquake and the Sun became as black
as sackcloth of hair and the moon became
as blood jump down with me to verse 15
and the kings of the earth and the great
men and the rich men and the chief
captains and the mighty men and every
bondman and every free man hid
themselves in the dens and in the rocks
of the mountains and said to the
mountains and rocks fall on us and hide
us from the face of him that sitteth on
the throne and from the wrath of the
lamb for the great day of his wrath has
come and who shall be able to stand do
you want to know why Jesus comes back
with such wrath you want to know why
because Satan was messing with his
ride-or-die people that's why he comes
back with such wrath in fact if you read
Revelation chapter 7 the Bible says that
he seals his people and protects them
from the coming calamities beloved your
your rider thy friend is going to do
everything in his power to protect you
and keep you and then and then he
returns but wait do you want to know how
he returns you want to know how he and
his armies returned from heaven coming
for his ride-or-die friends you want to
take a guess how many didn't know just
raise your hand easy how do you know how
he returns how army returns how do they
return he is riding a white horse his
armies
are on white horses and they're coming
for those who were ride-or-die do you
see why Jesus wants us so much to be his
rider thy friends he knew that we
couldn't be ride-or-die friends without
him first demonstrating it to us so he
says look I'm gonna be this for you I'm
gonna show you no yeah you were you were
you were you know disloyal to me you are
all these things for me but I was
willing to ride or die and not when we
see what he's done for us of the cross
he says now it's your turn ride or die
because beloved a rider died
relationship cannot be one way it's
gotta be both people that are ride and
die that's what truly makes it ride and
died imagine you you and your friend
yeah this is my ride and die and your
friend is like no that's not a ride or
die relationship
the rider dot is when you and your
friend are willing to go through thick
and thin together so so there's a verse
that we opened up with John 15:13
greater love has no man in this then he
lay his life down for his friend but
there's a verse right before that and in
the verse right before that Jesus says
check this out guys this are you ready
Jesus said just before that verse he
said this a new commandment I leave you
as I was willing to ride and die for you
so I want you do you know this is going
so I want you to ride or die for wait a
minute
the only supposed to have one ride or
die friend no not in my church in my
church by this the world shall know that
you are my disciples when you ride or
die for each other
Oh what would the church and look like
if we actually rode or die for each
other for I wonder what that was I'm
gonna be Wonder it's a shame that we
have to wonder that would look like I
want you to think about this Jesus is
telling us we need to ride or die for
each other because as I rode and died
for you we love Him because He first
other this busy and hearing we perceive
the love of God that we lay our life
down for the Brethren because he laid
his life down for us you see beloved the
reason the early church experienced the
outpouring of the Holy Spirit is because
the disciples in the upper room had a
ride-or-die relationship and it wasn't
with just their favorite people come on
how many of you have favorite people in
the church don't raise your hand which
is oh yeah oh yeah
them but ask my no no no it's not
supposed to be that way we are supposed
to pick out any two people in this room
and be like yeah are you right and die
we're right and die
that's how eternities do did you know
that worldly fraternities get right and
die sororities their right and die
friends in the world they're right and
die I have a group of friends you I've
told you about them before my friends
from back in college we are we haven't
seen many of them in years and you know
what guess what
ride and die that's just it right
can we say that in the church can you
say hey yeah
my church is ride-or-die
imagine if we could say that
imagine the witness we would have if we
could say my church rotted I rather die
everybody write or die you see whatever
listen many of us you know we have we
have people who disagree with us
disagree with us theologically and we're
like peace I illogically whatever it is
but we don't have that kind of
relationship Jesus was not he did not
ride and die for his friends while we
were yet sinners enemies think about the
division going on in God's church
because one person believes it this way
and the other person believes it that
way and so we're like you're going to
hell you know what beloved Jesus died
Jesus died for Pete Jesus rode and died
for people going to hell he went all out
for people going to hell so so I dare
say this you don't have to agree with
what someone else thinks or believes you
should still ride and Danny ride and die
does not mean I agree with your
philosophy I agree with your theology I
agree
ride or die means I love you as Jesus
loved me and then I hope you make it cuz
I want to ride with you but man I just
you know believing that I don't know but
I said I'm silver and I'm willing to
ride and die for you after
I wasn't gonna show this actually like
just happened have two friends that are
almost at the at the they are at the
opposite ends of the theological
spectrum and someone said something
about one of these friends and they too
are friends
they're friends but they are as far
apart as you can be and someone said
something derogatory about the one
friend on Facebook and these are people
with you know ministries or in ministry
and the one friend when he saw this he
says he was like hey I am standing on
behalf of my friend so-and-so this is
not true and he actually went on to say
we don't even agree theologically but
this is my man you will not do this
right or die
he didn't say right or die but you get
the idea how much different we think
about all the stuff we have going on in
church oh yeah they believe this way and
they believe that how different would
things be if we were right and die I'm
closing
Matthew chapter 5 Matthew chapter 5
verse 44 I'm gonna invite Eric where are
you entering to come up and Eric is
gonna lead us in prayer now if you
chapter 5 verse 44 the Bible says here
you've heard that it has been said thou
shalt love thy neighbour and hate thine
enemy but I say unto you love your
enemies bless them that curse you do
good to them that hate you pray for them
which despitefully use you and persecute
you that you may be the children of your
father which is in heaven God doesn't
call us to ride-or-die result for those
that we get along with for those that we
are cool with he calls us to ride or die
not only for one another not only when
we agree with one another he calls us to
ride or die check this out even for the
world wait a minute
the people that hate us and persecute it
yes I want you to ride or die for them
why for God so loved the church that he
gave I'm sorry for God so loved the
Christian that oh no no no oh wait for
God so loved who the world that He gave
His only begotten Son to ride or die for
them
when we love the world as Christ loved
the world then we know that we are
riding with Jesus my appeal to you today
is really three words
ride or die that's my view ride or die
someone it's a step further I'm gonna
ask you to do this if you have someone
in your life maybe someone that agree
that disagrees with you theologically
and you're just like you know you're not
I want you to do I want you to actually
do something
an enemy someone that you may not I want
you to text that person email that
person we're faced with what do we need
to do and just three words ride or die
and if they ask what it is then just
show them the sermon you guys want to
say but I'm just letting you know ride
or die
ride or die what you doing let me see if
you hate let me see hands if you're
gonna do it come on some of your already
struggling like man I don't want to tell
you right yes yes it's a good start
it's a good start but here's my second
appeal listen if you're saying today
lord help me to be right or die I I
thank you for riding and dying for me
help me help me to be a ride or die
friend to you and a ride or die friend
for us if you're ready to ride or die
I'm gonna invite you to stand I'm gonna
ask Eric to lead us in prayer will kneel
up here you stand and let's pray
you
we form our hearts to open us up to
loving one another as you have loved us
lord help us through your example that
you set here to show compassion and
mercy to those that we might not even
agree with you with us the Sabbath or as
we continue to try to follow your
example of who you call us to be
hopeless to show our right or dying
theologies through our actions as well
oh thank you for forgiving our sins
Jesus name I pray amen